INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER

Industrial Engineer graduate from one of the best private universities of Venezuela with experience in process analysis, basic aspects of cathodic protection, quality control of documentation of projects, development of Python programs, development of ML models and NN models and development of a maintenance plan for a FRICK RWB II Plus compressor. With the **following knowledge:**

· SPC (statistical process control) · Python3 · Pytest/Unittest · Django/DRF · JavaScript & TypeScript · ReactJS/NextJS · NestJs · Prisma · Ruby/Rails · Keras & Tensorflow/Theano · Pandas, Numpy & Matplotlib · Norms ISO 9001, 14001 · Six sigma (DMAIC/DMADV) · PERT-CPM · Cathodic protection (CP) · GCP

EDUCATION

Rafael Belloso Chacin University (URBE) · Maracaibo, Venezuela (2014) Industrial Engineer

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

TECH AND SOLVE • Remote (Sep. 2022 – Jan. 2023)

Digital transformation through software development projects and DevOps with agile as a methodological framework.

<u>Tech Lead Developer</u>: Led the development of a Python program that interacts with the Google Cloud Platform (GCP) API to extract and generate a file with the desired information for a start up company in Austin, TX.

- Development of a program using Python and Docker which allowed the client to easily extract the information they are interested in.
- Make use of the Google APIs libraries to interact with the platform and get the data.
- Manipulation of the data using Pandas, Numpy and Jupyter to get the desired output and generate a file that the client can use.
- Use of Pytest and Unittest mock tests to ensure the quality of the code.
- Make use of logging libraries to easily spot errors within the application and generate a log file.

FREELANCE · Remote (Apr. 2016 – Present)

<u>Self-Employed Python Developer</u>: Developed a variety of programs to automate repetitive tasks for my clients, predict possible outcomes, organize messy information and clean data. Have worked in projects that involve the use of statistics, reading and editing Excel tables, web scraping, data analysis, Machine Learning models and Neural Network models, NLP, and web development and design.

- **(2018) Klickwell –** Worked with client to develop a horse betting program that successfully reduce horse races to four horses, with a good accuracy rate for predicting the winning horse.
- (2019) Applying A.I to Klickwell Started the process of recollecting data to develop a Machine Learning Model as well as a Neural Network model to aid Klickwell to predict the winning horse.
- (2020) CRUD Website using RubyOnRails/Bootstrap/PostgreSQL Developed a small CRUD website following the Anki flashcard method using Ruby for the backend, Bootstrap for the frontend and Postgresql as database, to manage flashcards taken when studying.
- **(2021) E-commerce Website for client –** Worked on an E-commerce website using Django and Braintree as payment gateway where the client can buy the products listed and generate the order for the shipment.

- (2021 2022) Intraday crypto-trading bot Worked on an intraday crypto-trading bot that connects to the Binance API, retrieves and analyses the data and buys or sells the cryptocurrency depending on a trading strategy.
- (2022) E-commerce Website using NextJs/Tailwind/Typescript/PostgreSQL/DRF E-commerce website
 for selling physical and digital products using Paypal and/or Braintree as payment gateway. NextJS fetch the
 data from the Django API using Axios and display it on the page so the client can generate the desired
 order. Once the order is created, a POST method is send to the API and the order is created inside the
 database.
- Visit ngz91.github.io/NgzPortfolio/ to see some of my projects.

<u>Trainee of a Maritime Engineer specialized in corrosion (NACE Level 4)</u> · Houston, TX 77433 (Oct. 2015 – Jan. 2016): Acquired basic knowledge in the area of cathodic protection related to the analysis of the measurements that influence corrosion.

- Assistance to seminary about **cathodic protection (CP)** sponsored by NACE (National Association of Corrosion Engineers) international.
- **Visits in-field** with the NACE Level 4 engineer with the objective of familiarizing with the instruments used for the measurement process of corrosion.

LANGUAGES

· Spanish (Native) · English (High) · French (Intermediate) · Japanese (Basic)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

· Python3 · Pandas, Numpy & Matplotlib · Pytest & Unittest · Django/DRF · JavaScript & TypeScript · ReactJS/NextJS · NestJs · Prisma · HTML & CSS · Ruby/Rails · Keras & Scikit-Learn · Tensorflow & Theano • GCP